

Ilkka Kudjoi

Date of birth 18.1.1982

Curriculum Vitae

I have already eleven years of experience in the software industry in versatile tasks. Currently I'm more focused on backend, most of all on databases, but I have also been a Full Stack Developer. I love solving complex prolems, building CI/CD pipelines on database solutions and automating ETL processes. Feedback from customers has always been commendatory. I commute by bike almost every working day of the year and besides that I also live cross-country skiing, orienteering and also running without checkpoint targets. I also enjoy woodworks.

Education

2002-2007 Master of Science in Technology, Helsinki University of Technology

2006–2007 **Erasmus Exchange**, *University of Würzburg*

2001–2002 Military service, Kainuu Brigade, Kajaani

Master's thesis

Topic Applying the Gittins index to scheduling of a queueing system

Supervisors Esko Valkeila, Samuel Aalto

Description The objective of the thesis is to introduce reader to the Gittins index and

demonstrate, how it can be applied to manage a queueing system.

E-thesis http://web.lib.aalto.fi/fi/oa/db/INSSI/?cmd=get&id=35549

Employment

08/2019- **DW Product Owner**, ANALYSE²

As the product owner of our internal data warehouse and integration team I'm responsible of gathering internal and external requirements, writing user stories, task prioritization and roadmap planning. Currently we are transitioning our solution to Snowflake cloud, adopting modern CI/CD solutions and job orchestration.

01/2008-08/2019 Jack of All Trades, $Analyse^2$

During the first decade of my Analyse² career I've become a fully qualified software and database professional. I've taken care of various different responsibilities, including Team Lead, Product Owner and Technical Project Manager duties. Lately I've been focusing on integration, CI/CD, cloud adoption and data warehousing but I started as a Full Stack developer. Please see my LinkedIn profile for details.

03/2007–12/2007 **Research Assistant**, HELSINKI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY I worked at Networking Laboratory writing my Master's Thesis.

09/2003-12/2005 Course assistant, Helsinki University of Technology

As an course assistant I was responsible of conducting weekly exercise sessions for undergraduate students in different courses on mathemathics courses L1 and L2.

05/2004–08/2004 **Research Assistant**, HELSINKI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY I made two special assignments during two consecutive summers at the Laboratory of Computer and Information Science at TKK.

05/2003-08/2003 Research Assistant, Helsinki University of Technology

Programming skills

Languages C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, Ruby, & Technologies .NET, .NET Core, AWS, & CloudFormation, Docker, Git, Scripting & Gitlab

OS Linux, Windows Database MSSQL, Snowflake

Methods Object-oriented programming, TDD, IaC, Data Vault, Continuous integration& (TeamCity, GitLab), Agile methods, ScrumPatterns

Languages

Native Finnish

Good English German Swedish

Basics Russian

Links

Master's thesis

Linkedin